<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Other | Captain's Log]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.captainslog.me/blog/categories/other/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.captainslog.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-22T11:55:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.captainslog.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jon Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enable Thunderbird Global Search in Fedora]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2010/09/16/enabled-thunderbird-global-search-in-fedora/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-16T14:38:35-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2010/09/16/enabled-thunderbird-global-search-in-fedora</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;ve just installed Thunderbird on Fedora 13, you&rsquo;ve probably noticed the Global Search bar is missing.  At least, this is one of the first things I noticed. After using Thunderbird 3.x for sometime on Windows I&rsquo;ve really come to love this feature.</p>

<p>It seems the default configuration on Fedora doesn&rsquo;t enable this feature by default, however it is simple to get working.  Go to the Preferences menu, Advanced section and check &ldquo;Enable Global Search and Indexer&rdquo;.  After this, restart Thunderbird and it will begin indexing your mail.  After which, the Global Search should work as expected.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Storage Server]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2009/10/22/open-source-storage-server/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-22T21:29:28-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2009/10/22/open-source-storage-server</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is not going to be a full review, but more a general take on things.</p>

<p>Since moving from VMware Server to ESXi to host my virtual machines, I&rsquo;ve been very interested in looking into some more of the advanced features of ESX and ESXi yet most of these require iSCSI.  I remember from a few years back using <a href="http://openfiler.com/">Openfiler</a> to do some simple samba file sharing, and remembered it supported iSCSI as one method of giving out storage.</p>

<p>Now, I&rsquo;ve yet to use any of the features of ESX that require iSCSI, or even setup <a href="http://openfiler.com/">Openfiler</a> to export storage via iSCSI, but I have been using it for simple file sharing and must say I&rsquo;m quite impressed.</p>

<p>Setup is a breeze, taking about 20 minutes on an older PC. Management is done almost entirely through a <a href="http://openfiler.com/products/screenshots/">web interface</a>, that is very easy to use.  Unlink many of the other appliance packages out there, the web interface is very simple and straight forward.  Very much impressed with that.</p>

<p>Over the next few months I&rsquo;ll be exploring <a href="http://openfiler.com/">Openfiler</a> much more, and hopefully getting into some of it&rsquo;s more advanced features including interface bonding, md devices and clustering.  I plan to keep updating as things more along.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every Administrator Needs Two Accounts..]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2008/12/31/every-administrator-needs-two-accounts/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-31T22:32:33-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2008/12/31/every-administrator-needs-two-accounts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I assume you&rsquo;ve had your hands on at least one set of administrative credentials in your life.  I&rsquo;d also make the assumption that you&rsquo;ve used that account as your <em>everyday account</em>.  You know, the one we use to check mail, surf the web, update facebook, download porn&hellip; you know, that kind of stuff.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s a <strong>bad</strong> idea.</p>

<p>Why, you might ask.  Doing so, opens yourself up for quite a lot of trouble.</p>

<p>Time to take a step back&hellip;. Let&rsquo;s imagine for a moment that you&rsquo;re just another user.  What kind of access would you have on the network?  Hopefully you&rsquo;ve just said &lsquo;as little as possible&rsquo; or &lsquo;only what you need&rsquo; or similar.  Well, why is that?  Security.  The idea of least access says that I can do only what I need to do to complete my job.</p>

<p><strong>Whoa! But I&rsquo;m the admin!</strong> I <em>need</em> access to everything!</p>

<p>This may be true, but probably not.  Think about your average day.  What do you really do?  Occasionally you install some software, create user accounts, update systems&hellip; the list can go on.  Now, let&rsquo;s really think about that&hellip; How often do those tasks happen and where do you perform them.  Know that you&rsquo;ve answered those questions, let&rsquo;s move on.</p>

<p>Everyone on your network should have a user account.  That is, a limited account with least access to the resources they need.  For an administrator, this means you have an account with very limited access to install software, run updates, make system changes and the like.  Just like everyone else.  This is the account you work with daily.  You log in, surf the web, read the news, send email, check blogs, etc&hellip; all that work stuff.</p>

<p><strong>BUT WAIT</strong></p>

<p>You also create an account for yourself with administrative rights.  This account, is used whenever you need to perform an administrative task.</p>

<p>Have this account separate account means that any time you want to do something that requires administrative access you MUST think &ldquo;Do I really want to do this&rdquo;?  I bet you find yourself saying &ldquo;no, not really&rdquo; quite a lot after this.  Separate accounts also gives you a nice way of monitoring changes on your network.  By having separate logins, you can see when (and who) is making administrative changes on your network.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m tired..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Insightful Comic..]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2008/11/14/another-insightful-comic/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-14T08:50:56-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2008/11/14/another-insightful-comic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reading the feeds today, and came across todays <a href="http://xkcd.com/504/">xkcd comic</a>.  Very funny.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AsylumLAN 33 - November 15-16]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2008/10/20/asylumlan-33-november-15-16/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-20T16:55:28-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.captainslog.me/blog/2008/10/20/asylumlan-33-november-15-16</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s that time ago.  Another AsylumLAN is set for the middle of November.   If you&rsquo;re into gaming I highly recommend this event.  Details below or check out their website for more information.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Date</strong>: Nov 15-16, 2008<img src="http://www.asylumlan.com/images/stories/logos/aldatepanel.png" alt="" /></p></li>
<li><p><strong>Time</strong>: Sat 10am - Sunday 4pm</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Cost</strong>: $30 pre-register, $35 walk-in</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Location</strong>: Vanderburgh Co. 4H</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Registration now open at <a href="http://www.asylumlan.com">asylumlan.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
